hey what's up thanks for listening to
the grory Life podcast I'm excited that
you're here I'm excited to talk today
about a break through that I had
recently um it's actually just a couple
of hours ago but it's something that I
got a it sounds funny saying that but
it's something that I have had
breakthroughs in constantly in
consistently over my life and I
remembered something that I just always
end up going back to and that I need to
remind myself how I need to like plaster
it on the wall for and I hope that this
encourages you when I share this
breakthrough with you that I had that it
might encourage you as well to have the
same breakthrough you know in life we
have stuff that happens things don't go
how we want them to if you lived on
planet Earth you know that you could do
all the right things and yet stuff won't
work out how we wish they did and that
can be devastating it it can suck
but here's the
thing we can't let what happened to us
Define us and our future and where we're
going and what we're
doing and that's not to negate or to say
that it didn't happen or that it didn't
hurt or that it wasn't hard and that's
the key accept that but don't blame it
don't play the victim don't walk in that
victim mentality gosh I was walking in a
victim mentality
for so long what is a victim mentality
again it's it's saying well I can't do
what I want to do because they or that
thing the algorithm doesn't work how I
want it to or those people aren't
showing up how I want or Facebook shut
me
down and I see people they do this all
the time or my wife demands this of me
or my kids are acting this way and we
end up blaming everything that's around
us for why we're not experiencing the
life that we want to live instead of
saying okay you know what taking
ownership I created this life I created
this world this is the world that I want
to live in and not playing the victim of
saying that all this stuff is happening
to hurt us but rather realizing that
it's actually a for our benefit which
can be hard to say it's like you know
that's a difficult thing to say we're
like okay well no it's not for my
benefit that this happened but in the
long term it is if you let it be a
teacher to you and number
two is realizing that how everything is
going in your life right now is because
of a series of choices that you made
it's a series of events that you made
and can we beat ourselves up for that
can we feel like we're we're oh I'm so
ashamed and and and fall flat in our
face or we become upset because people
aren't responding how we quote unquote
need them to or want them to again I've
done this and I've experienced this
myself
it's not pretty it's not healthy and
it's not a way to live
life and so I want to encourage you you
probably got some big goals if you're
like me you got a lot of big stuff that
you want to do you got stuff that you
want to
accomplish break it down into smaller
tasks number
one and do step by step and then figure
out which of those steps is taking you
longer this is one of the biggest
breakthrough strategies
that I use all the time is I look at of
the big picture how does it break down
to smaller steps and then of those
smaller steps which ones am I taking the
longest on what am I stuck on what do I
feel the resistance around so then when
you can identify one or two areas where
you have
resistance and and listen if you're like
me you probably got a lot more than one
or two here's one of the things you want
to be careful of don't try to tackle all
of those things at once just identify
the one that really Rises up to the
surface the most that you notice in
every part of your life so start to
develop your pattern
recognition um muscles because in
business you need to know how to do
pattern recognition but what you can do
is you can identify a pattern of how
we're behaving over here how that's
affecting us over here and we can start
to find and identify okay where that
roote is for me I found a pattern of
behavior
that I didn't like for the
last two months y two months it was uh
it it started in at the end of
June and I'm just like why is this
happening why does this keep happening
and I and I know a series of events that
took place at the beginning middle and
end of June and I was blaming those
things for why things were happening in
a certain way for me now here's the cool
part about it right now as of
today I can look back
at success is a lagging indicator of the
actions that we take and I can look back
at what I'm doing today and I can see
the trajectory of what's happening in my
life going forward it's amazing I can
look back though for the
last two months six months and I can see
why maybe there was a certain struggle
as far as that goes you know my wife
she's about to give birth
here very
soon and that's shaken our life up and
so i' I've had to get
real serious about what is the life we
want to live how do we envision it and
then start
working in building and creating that
life and it comes from not blaming
everything around us one of the big
biggest things I was blaming is my wife
and my kids for not having the kind of
life or business that I wanted now this
sounds crazy but live hear me
out I found myself dialoguing that there
was a version of how I would build how I
was building my business before my son
was
born and now for the last two years I've
not been able to build my business in
that way I'll tell you this moving
forward I'm going to be able to because
I know exactly why that is and what I
need to do differently it's it's just a
different way of building it that's it
and so what we got to do is we got to
learn to adapt we got to learn to go
with the flow of the change in the
situations so no matter what situation
life throws at you learn to be adaptable
instead of being like
Oh again the other shoe dropped and it
just uh nothing goes my way you know I
hear people all the time when I'm
coaching them they say this they use
this they speak out of their mouth
against their life
negatively things don't go how I want
them to things don't go how I need them
to Facebook shut me down Facebook
blocked me the algorithm didn't do what
I needed it
to and we end up
blaming the stuff that we're
experiencing you know I used to teach
this to people um and they would get
really offended by by what I just said
they're like you have no empathy
Jeremiah for anybody's situation I'm
like actually the problem is I probably
have way too much empathy for it and
unfortunately when I dive way too deep
and cross into sympathy I start thinking
and operating in a way that is not
healthy because it's not healthy to play
the victim it's not healthy to play and
when I say Play It's living your life as
somebody who is
powerless we have so much more power in
our pinky finger than we ever imagin you
have so much more power than you could
ever possibly imagine but do you believe
that I'll tell you this when you can
learn to listen to your inner
voice what does that look like that
means calming the nervous system down
that means bringing the anxiety down
learning how to control the internal
anxiousness and this can be a journey
and it's not easy but it's worth it to
learn how to bring your anxiousness down
and I'll tell you I look back at because
I I had been in therapy for two and a
half
years full transparency now I actually
have been using uh chat
GPT uh I'll I'll tell it to act as if
it's a therapist trained in internal
family systems and CBT and is it as good
as a therapist
no but what I'm doing is I'm training my
mind and I'm using this tool on demand
anytime something comes up I can talk
about it with the AI and and I find it's
extremely helpful I find there's a huge
benefit I find most of my breakthroughs
don't come from those sessions but they
come afterwards when I consider what I'm
going through like tonight I was
thinking about I'm blame I've been
blaming my wife and my son
again for why my business isn't where I
would want to cuz I'm like I would be
able to do this and I'll be able to do
this be able to
do
well I can still do those things but but
are the consequences what I want right
now well no is the life that I have
right now with my family the life that
I'm wanting well yes okay great and and
our life is incredible right now we're
making more money than we ever made in
our
life
but I know there's more and I know
there's a greater level and I know
there's a a a new place that I want to
go you I was just talking to a friend of
mine today and I and I had asked him I
actually felt it uh inside of me to call
him I I felt you should call this friend
you should ask him this is a friend
who's uh massively gone from where we
were working together a couple years ago
to Major levels of success
Beyond and I just asked him I said hey
what's the biggest shift that's happened
for you and he literally just reminded
me of something that I knew
already that was exactly what I needed
to hear in that moment and and and the
biggest shift
was to to to not just see the reality
that you want but to start to be the
person that is experiencing those things
and then to start to map it out and be
intentional with the things that you
want in your life
life and then he said this and it's a
bit of more of a spiritual term but he
said
to service the altar that got you to
where you want to be to where you are to
where you are that's what he said now
what does that mean let's let's unpack
that that means doing the things that
got you to where you are and continuing
to do those things for him it was just
massive amount of prayer for me I can
look back at gosh prayer is a huge one
for me of course it is there's other
little habits too because once I can
hear my inner voice God's voice and I
believe that me and God become
interconnected
together my intuition my my Holy Spirit
starts to hear and I say intuition and
holy spirit they're not the same thing
they work in tandem that's how I see it
they they work together I I find
intuition to be kind of like my part and
then I think there's a there's a a holy
spirit a higher power a source God that
we can connect with and hear from I'm
not here to preach but I think I think
everybody can I've know a lot of people
that didn't believe in that for the
longest time and then they went through
a lot of similar experiences like I have
I did not believe that for the longest
time longest time I didn't think that
God could talk to me that way and now I
know that he
can you got to remember who you
are you got to remember your power and
you got to realize you're not
powerless stuff happens things don't go
how we want them to things don't turn
out how we want them to all the time
that's okay
it's okay it is it's going to be okay
it's going to work out it's going to
come together and when you can start to
walk in that walk in that that hope and
that favor and that
Clarity your actions will follow in a
way that turns your life around and you
will start to notice synchronicities
that
happen those are kind of
cool you will start to experience
changes in your
life and I think what ends up happening
is we end up literally
Shifting the Atmosphere around us and we
start attracting more of the life that
we were meant to live it's not just what
we want it's by the way what we want
might not be healthy for us but it's the
what we were meant
for and that's a big one and I know some
of you know that there's a difference
between what you want how you thought it
was going to come in
how many of y'all had have have had a
dream and a desire in your life and it
didn't come in through the way that you
thought it
would I have so many of
those and so now for me like when things
don't go how I want them to or things
don't work out I start to get
excited and it's a that's a that's a
that's a mindset to get into that's that
will change your life to start to get
excited when
things get a little
chaotic when things
don't necessarily work out the way you
wish I had some situations today that
happened incredible weird situations but
you know what they didn't throw us off
they didn't Define us in a certain way
they didn't change my wife and mine's
Faith because we know where we're going
and we're trusting the process and we're
and we're trusting that God's going to
direct our footsteps We're Not Afraid
and we're going to take risks and we're
going to step out and we're start to do
the thing that we know that we need to
do and we're not just going to stop
there we're going to keep doing the
thing over and over again we can think
about doing it but actually doing it
actually stepping up actually taking
action that's what produces the results
that we want in our life and so listen
if you're listening to this podcast
right now I do this podcast every single
week
you'll notice that some of the episodes
got a different vibe all the time you
can literally you can some of y'all if
you've listened to all my episodes you
can track where I'm at mentally and
emotionally based on how certain
trainings I do
are
um you can accomplish anything that you
want in your
life and it doesn't have to be hard
and when we can stop blaming everything
around us when we can stop playing the
victim to all of our situations you know
I can sit here recording this podcast
and play the victim to all my listeners
well I'm not going to say this because
this might piss somebody off I'm not
going to say this because they might not
like it okay who cares that person's
never going to listen to it anyways why
am I concerned about that and just keep
speaking the truth how I know
it if this has helped you in some way
please share this episode with
somebody please don't just hold this
back to
yourself and if you're a coach course
creator trainer I'd love to work with
you in our accelerator program to help
you dial in your messaging your Niche
your sales your advertising your offers
and all of that to help you have
consistent
Clarity maximize your
impact huge cash flow and start to bring
things together so that you can have the
financial and time Freedom that you want
that's what we do every single week with
our clients in our accelerator program
and I want to help you with that well
all right this has been the grow like
podcast talk soon going
[Applause]
[Music]